<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vanneistat on Isak's Blog</title><link>https://blog.isakkvam.com/tags/vanneistat/</link><description>Recent content in Vanneistat on Isak's Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.isakkvam.com/tags/vanneistat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cory Doctorow's writing routine</title><link>https://blog.isakkvam.com/post/cory-doctorows-writing-routine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isakkvam.com/post/cory-doctorows-writing-routine/</guid><description>&lt;p>Cory Doctorow is one of those writers who&amp;rsquo;s able to write so much so quickly, I&amp;rsquo;m left scratching my head.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve only read one of his 30 or so fiction and non-fiction books — &lt;em>The Lost Cause&lt;/em> — and while that&amp;rsquo;s already a prolific catalog, the guy also writes not one but two blogs. &lt;em>Pluralistic&lt;/em>, his daily link blog, intimidates me: how does this guy have &lt;em>so much&lt;/em> to say every day? And how can he balance this with writing books, finding interesting articles on the internet, and maintain a life with chores, eating, and sleeping?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I did what anybody would do: I read a bunch of essays and interviews with him while watching figure skating on the Olympics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Perfection is an act of cowardice</title><link>https://blog.isakkvam.com/post/perfectionism-is-an-act-of-cowardice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.isakkvam.com/post/perfectionism-is-an-act-of-cowardice/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve been following Van Neistat’s videos since his fifth video was published, which the YouTube algorithm suggested while I was vanning through Walla Walla, Washington. I was killing time hanging out by the river and, having watched most of his brother Casey’s daily vlogs (rip daily vlogs), quickly watched all his videos beginning to end.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He can get ranty. He can be cranky. He has plenty of opinions I don’t agree with. But his videos about the creative process are fascinating.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His latest, about the struggles of perfectionism as a creative person and working toward “good enough” or “excellent,” is so relatable:&lt;/p>

 &lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dBqK6e9A9bE?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;p>I usually operate in the “good enough” camp (ESPECIALLY blogging) with regular forays into attempting excellence (usually for work).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>